# **ALEXANDER CURNOW**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER



(609) 412-8578



alexcurnow@gmail.com



alexcurnow.netlify.app



github.com/alexcurnow



linkedin.com/in/alexcurnow

## **PROFILE**

My introduction to software development was initially sparked by my band's manager, himself a web developer. The things he could do blew my mind. I'd always have twenty question for him, but never really understood his answers. My curiosity was piqued, and a few Codecademy and Udemy courses later I applied to NSS hungry to learn more. For me, the most enticing aspect of being a software engineer is that the learning is truly endless, and I'm constantly eager for the next challenge!

## **Solo Projects**

## Cativity

A cat activity tracker that helps users stick to a regular playtime routine with their pet, with the intended result being life with a happier, healthier, and more predictably calm cat.

- Built with React JS
- Focused on a mobile responsive design in order to practice component state management in a limited display area
- Utilized third party dependencies like Cloudinary (for image upload), and Material UI for layout and design

## **LANGUAGES**

**English Spanish** 

## SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE

## **Software Engineer**

Nashville Software School | Nashville, TN

2/20 - 8/20

Intensive full-time 6 month software development bootcamp with intensive learning in both individual and team-based projects. Tech stack includes: C#/ .NET; React.js; Javascript; HTML5; CSS3; Flexbox; Git; GitHub; SQL fundamentals.

Front end dashboard app that helps users keep track of their daily tasks, events, news articles, friends, and chat messages.

- Created a flat-structured database in which to store user data
- Utilized JSON Server to host a REST API, make fetch requests, and populate relevant data points based on user interaction
- Handled user-generated and custom events
- Implemented relational data for more robust functionality
- Leveraged GitHub to optimize remote team workflow

## DogGo

A beautifully simple dog walking app that helps busy dog owners connect with dog walkers in their local area.

- Utilized SQL Express for database
- Leveraged ASP.NET Core's MVC capabilities to connect the user to relevant data endpoints based on the user's selections
- Implemented View Models to handle displaying relation data for a more robust user experience

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Bar Manager**

Bajo Sexto Taco | Nashville, TN

5/2018 - 2/2020

- Promoted to bar manager from bar tender
- Leader of three person bar tending team
- Tracked & ordered inventory for entire bar
- Worked with manager, sales reps, and distributors to identify cost saving opportunities
- Assisted and supported front of house with orders and food running
- Assumed role of shift leader as needed, including all associated closing responsibilities (counting and closing the register, preparing the deposit, filling out end of day sales reports)

### **Landscaping Manager**

Go To Guy | Nashville, TN

4/2015 - 10/2017

- Promoted to landscaping manager from landscaping specialist
- Managed a team of up to three landscaping specialists
- Coordinated team workflow for efficient completion of jobs
- Responsible for work truck and all equipment (loading and prep for beginning and end of day)

## **Freelance Musician**

Nashville, TN

7/2014 - present

- Taught guitar lessons to students from beginner to advanced
- Managed band rehearsals, social media, releases, marketing, and merchandise
- Booked shows locally including multiple tours around the south and northeast

### **EDUCATION**

Nashville Software School - Full Stack Software Developer Longy School of Music - Masters in Modern American Music University of Rhode Island - BS in Marketing, BA in Jazz Studies